



Mahlet Sewinet Admasu

Nationality: Ethiopian Date of birth: 31/10/2000

Complex of the Complex of the Comp

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahi- sewinet-028452207/

• Home: Ras Hotel Rd, Bishoftu (Ethiopia)

ABOUT ME

I have graduated with very great distinction in computer science from AAU University, which is well-known for its academic excellence. I gained a strong foundation in both theoretical and practical skills. Obtaining a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science with an outstanding CGPA of 3.75 demonstrates my commitment and competence in the field. Along with my academic accomplishments, I also hold a year of work experience as an Associate Engineer with a focus on web development and knowledge of Firebase and Angular.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior It officer

Bunna banksc [01/02/2024 - Current]

City: Addis Ababa Country: Ethiopia

- Creating and Managing identity and access of the bank staff on core banking system.
- Maintaining the security of in house developed applications at the bank .

Customer Service Officer

Oromia Bank [18/10/2023 - 25/01/2024]

City: Dukem **Country:** Ethiopia

- Process deposit and withdrawal.
- Opening Accounts for customers.

Associate Engineer

Nasheed Station(PVT) Ltd [01/11/2022 - 15/11/2023]

City: Rawalpindi **Country:** Pakistan

- Development and implementation of front-end features using Angular framework.
- Bug fixing and troubleshooting.
- Data management and synchronization between angular front-end and Firebase back-end.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Amharic

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Addis Ababa University [2019 – 2023]

City: Addis Ababa Country: Ethiopia

Website: http://www.aau.edu.et/ Final grade: CGPA 3.75 / 4.00

Graphic designing training

Orange digital center

City: Addis Ababa Country: Ethiopia

Website: https://www.orangedigitalcenters.com/

Modern software development tools

Orange digital center

City: Addis Ababa Country: Ethiopia

Website: https://www.orangedigitalcenters.com/

RECOMMENDATIONS

Lecturer at Computer Science Department Addis Ababa University

Name: Beimnet Girma

Email: beimnet.girma@aau.edu.et

Lecturer, final year project advisor and mentor.

Lecturer at Computer Science Department Addis Ababa University

Name: Yoseph Berhanu

Email: yoseph.berhanu@aau.edu.et

Lecturer and mentor.

DIGITAL SKILLS

JAVA / C++ / PHP / C# / PYTHON / UNIX / MYSQL / HTML / CSS / BOOTSTRAP / ANGULAR / SPRING BOOT / JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT / DOCKER / MONGODB / SQL / GRAPHICS DESIGNING / MICROSOFT OFFICE

DEVELOPMENT TOOL

VISUAL STUDIO CODE / GIT / POSTMAN

VOLUNTEERING

Teaching kids introduction to programming at koder lab.

[Atse Naod School, Addis Ababa]

Participating on welcoming of freshman students at AAU.

[Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia]

Served as a committee of AAU gender club.

[Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia]

Participated on cleaning of the AAU, CNCS campus.

[Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia]

Lead language and special needs devision of the three AAU campuses' Orthodox student union under Mahebere Kidusan.

[Holy Trinity church, 4 kilo, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia]

PROJECTS

Nasheed station website

[01/11/2022 - 15/11/2023]

Online Cinema and Theater ticket booking website

[10/12/2022 - 20/06/2023]

Implemented online ticket booking for Ethiopian cinemas and theaters using Angular and Spring boot

Ethiopian Food Recipe

[10/11/2022 - 16/01/2023]

android app made with java that show Ethiopian Food recipes, with their ingredients

Edir system

[03/11/2021 - 10/01/2022]

A C++ project that automates the manual edir system by transitioning it to a computer-based system.

Edir is a traditional community organization whose members assist each other during the mourning process.

Hagre Megeb bet

[11/06/2021 - 28/06/2021]

- A website that show case local food house services
- used Bootstrap to create a responsive website